gfmd.info 2019-03-21

# Privacy and Content Reuse Policy – [BETA] Global Forum for Media Development (GFMD)

This privacy and content reuse policy describes the Global Forum for Media Development’s (GFMD) policies and practices regarding its collection and use of your personal data in line with the guidelines set forth in the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation ([GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/)). It also contains our content reuse and licensing policies.

### **Using this site**

By visiting the GFMD website – located at: [https://gfmd.info](https://gfmd.info/) – you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions that follow.

### **Content reuse and copyright policy**

All content available on the GFMD website is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International license ([CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/)). Under this license, you are free to copy, distribute, and display this work and to make derivative works, provided you:

  * **Follow the reuse policy detailed in this section of the privacy and content reuse policy;**
  * **Do not use any work(s) derived from this publication for commercial purposes; and**
  * Distribute any work(s) derived from this publication under a license identical to this one.

If any party would like to republish any of GFMD’s content on a blog, website, or other platform, they can do so by adding the following to any piece of reused content:

“This article was originally published by the Global Forum for Media Development.”

Please include the direct link to the original article page, and indicate the author’s name if applicable as well as the day, month, and year of publication. An example of what a reused GFMD article should include is as follows: _This article was originally published by the_ _Global Forum for Media Development_ _on 1 January 2018._

In case GFMD reuses any piece of content from a third-party, including a member or partner organisation, we will credit the original author and publisher, and state the original publishing date along with a link to the original article in line with our own reuse request.

### **What personal data we collect and why we collect it**

We are committed to protecting your privacy. The following information explains why personal data is collected.

**Comments**

GFMD reserves the right to feature comments on our blog and other parts of the website. When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the [Gravatar](https://en.gravatar.com/) service to see if you are using it, and in line with their [privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Content forms and newsletter**

We collect and store data that is voluntarily shared with us when a user registers to receive our news, updates, and the MediaDev Insider Newsletter via our MailChimp newsletter subscription service, which is in line with MailChimp’s [privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/?_ga=2.174620192.303637169.1535549373-2126019454.1525351800).

The only information you are required to share when subscribing to our updates is an email address. You may also include your first name, surname, and organisation based on your preferences, but this information is not required.

Note that if you sign up for our newsletter and updates, you can change your mind at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email you receive from us. We will treat your information with respect.

**Cookies**

A “cookie” is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser that is stored by your device’s browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies are used, among other purposes, to help the website analyse how users use the site.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address, and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one (1) year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two (2) days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me,” your login will persist for two (2) weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after one (1) day

**Cookies employed by GFMD**

GFMD employs the necessary cookies to make the website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website, which are in line with the [privacy policy](https://wordpress.org/about/privacy/) of wordpress.org. Moreover, certain plugins for WordPress and other features on our website may use cookies for a limited number of purposes (see below).

**Analytics**

This website also employs [Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com/analytics/web/), a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., which makes use of cookies. The information generated by the cookie includes data about your use of the website (including your IP address), and is transmitted to and stored by Google who uses this information for the purposes of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators, and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage.

Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using the GFMD website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above and in line with the Google Inc.’s [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) and Google Analytics [terms of service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html).

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g., videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. 

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Links to third-party websites**

Within this website we include links to third party advice that may be of use to our visitors. When using the site, you may gain access to other websites through use of links or hypertext. In using the GFMD website, you agree that GFMD is not responsible for:

  * **Any advice given by third-party organisations;**
  * **For the content or operation of such third party websites; or**
  * Any security or privacy violations incurred by a third-party website

GFMD, to the extent permissible by law, excludes all liability that may arise from your use or reliance on the information or contents contained in the linked site.

**Do not track**

GFMD does not intentionally track its visitors when they cross to third-party websites, nor do we provide targeted advertising to website visitors.

If you have any privacy or cookie technology-related concerns, you may set your web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. You may also set your browser to refuse any cookies our site may attempt to send you, as well as enable [Do Not Track](https://www.eff.org/issues/do-not-track) settings in your browser. For more information on how to opt out, please contact us at: [communications@gfmd.info](mailto:communications@gfmd.info).

### **Data sharing information: Who we share your data with**

We never sell, lease, or rent your data.

We do not share your information with third-party services unless stated otherwise in this privacy policy. We reserve the right to share data with our members and partners, but only limited to first name, surname, email address, organisation, and position/title.

**How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website, we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**Where we send your data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service built into our WordPress theme. We do not currently employ a separate plugin dedicated to spam detection.

### **Social media**

The GFMD website interfaces with five social media websites: Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Medium, and YouTube. If you choose to comment, “like,” follow, tweet, or share information from the GFMD website through these services, we encourage you to review the privacy policy of the respective service you interact with. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.

While we encourage engagement with our social media profiles, bear in mind that that they are public fora and any information provided will be visible to the public. Therefore, please do not include personal details such as your email address, mobile number, or any other personal information that you do not want available to the general public.

While some Personally Identifying Information (PII) may become available to GFMD through your use of social media, we will not be collecting, sharing, or storing that information.

Our presence on these social media sites is not intended to endorse, recommend, or favor any third-party company or service provider. We also remind you to comply with each platform’s terms and conditions.

### **Security information and how we protect your data**

We are committed to your security, especially due to the sensitive nature of some of our and our members’ work. This is why all GFMD content is delivered over HTTPS. We also employ other security measures including WordPress plugins such as but not limited to [iThemes Security](https://ithemes.com/security/) and other measures to ensure our website users are protected to the extent that GFMD and our hosting service can provide.

If a data breach occurs, we will work with our host provider, our website developer, and the relevant authorities to investigate the breach. This includes when it occurred and what data (if any) was copied or stolen. We will then reach out to our registered members and any other parties with information stored in our website database to notify them of the breach and the steps and measures we are taking to both improve our security as well as identify the party(ies) that breached us.

### **iThemes Security Plugin Data Privacy information**

What personal data we collect and why we collect it

**Cookies**

Visiting the login page sets a temporary cookie that aids compatibility with some alternate login methods. This cookie contains no personal data and expires after 1 hour.

**Security Logs**

The IP address of visitors, user ID of logged in users, and username of login attempts are conditionally logged to check for malicious activity and to protect the site from specific kinds of attacks. Examples of conditions when logging occurs include login attempts, log out requests, requests for suspicious URLs, changes to site content, and password updates. This information is retained for fourteen (14) days.

**Who we share your data with**

This site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by Sucuri’s SiteCheck. We do not send personal information to Sucuri; however, Sucuri could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during their scan. For more details, please see [Sucuri’s privacy policy](https://sucuri.net/privacy).

**How long we retain your data**

Security logs are retained for fourteen (14) days.

### **Additional information about our website**

The GFMD website is built on WordPress, and employs a number of plugins such as [BuddyPress](https://buddypress.org/).

This website is hosted by [Greenhost](https://greenhost.net/), which is registered in the Netherlands, and our website is subject to the Greenhost [privacy policy](https://greenhost.net/about-us/terms-and-conditions/). Greenhost is also committed to ensuring website security, which is outlined in their [security and privacy page](https://greenhost.net/privacy/).

### **Changes and updates to this privacy policy**

By using this website or otherwise communicate with GFMD, you agree to the terms and conditions contained in this privacy and content reuse policy.

We recognize that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility; thus, we may modify or revise these terms and conditions and any related policies to ensure GFMD and this privacy policy reflect new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.

### **How to contact us**

GFMD is an international non-profit organisation (ASBL) registered in Brussels, Belgium.

If you have any questions or concerns about any of GFMD’s personal data policies or practices, please email us at: [communications@gfmd.info](mailto:communications@gfmd.info). You may also contact us via phone at: +32 (0) 2 234 63 06.

You may also contact our data protection officer:

Michael J. Oghia  
Advocacy and Engagement Manager  
Global Forum for Media Development  
Rond Point Schuman 6, Box 5  
Brussels 1040, Belgium  

_This privacy and content reuse policy was last updated on 13 March 2019_
